emarketingassociation.com 2013-11-16

# eMarketing Association | Privacy

This privacy statement describes the practices is applicable to [www.eMarketingAssociation.com](http://www.emarketingassociation.com/) a website managed jointly by the eMarketing Association and its licensee the Electronic Marketing Association, LLC,  (collectively referred to at the eMA).  This statement does not apply to information we collect offline.

The terms outlined in this privacy policy may be updated over time. If we make a material change to the way we handle your personal information, we will notify you of that change via the email address we have on file for you.

**Your Information: What, How, and Why?**

**Members and Visitors**

When you sign up on our site, which means you register to receive a newsletter, become a member, choose to have access to content, make a purchase, request additional information from the eMA or an advertiser, sponsor or client, you are signing up to receive communications from EMA and/or its advertisers, sponsors or clients. Specifically, you agree to:

Receive communication by e-mail (on behalf of the eMA or our advertisers);

Receive communication by postal mail (either from the eMA or our advertisers);

Receive communication by telephone (either from the eMA or our advertisers);

Receive communication by Fax (facsimile) (from the eMA);

Receive communications with special messages, administrative messages, or announcements;

Your information is maintained in a secure environment and is not shared with other partners except in those cases that are outlined in this statement and/or disclosed during a registration process.  The eMA employs a professional and secure e-mail hosting service to deliver e-mail newsletters and advertisements.

You may choose to discontinue receiving communications from the eMA. For specific instructions on how to opt out of future communications, instructions are included in every e-mail or group communication.  For additional details, continue reading below.

**eMA Member Profiles**

When you sign up to participate in the eMA Community by providing additional information which upon approval by the eMA will be added to your business profile, we will collect personal and business information to establish your profile. This profile will be used by the eMA in accordance with this privacy statement.

You may choose to make certain profile elements public, in which case that information would be available to anyone who visits the eMA website and (potentially) to other users of the Internet.

If you post or otherwise add information to the eMA, it can be viewed by anyone online. Your postings and information will be linked to your username and to your public profile, if you establish one.

**What Information Is Collected?**

Any information that you provide during registration, including your full name, mailing address, e-mail address, company name, phone number, industry, and job title.

IP Addresses, which are automatically provided by your web browser to our servers.

Information made available through the use of cookies or pixel tags (see below for more information about cookies and/or pixel tags).

Information you submit via community forums, forms, requests  and /or profile enhancements, such as the eMA business profile descriptions.

**How May the Information Be Used and/or Shared?**

Demographic information is used in aggregate (i.e., non-individual-specific) form to attract more relevant advertisers to improve the customer experience.

Specific data points (e.g., job title, business profile data, survey results) may be used to enable us to better serve our customers’ needs through product enhancements and improved communication.

Information you provide may be shared with vendors specifically to provide a service (e.g.,newsletter delivery). The information is shared only to the extent necessary to complete the transaction you requested.

Information posted to community forums (along with any personal or company information that you include in a public business profile) will be generally available to anyone on the Internet.

**Personally Identifiable Consumer or Business Information**

In addition, we may collect information that you choose to provide to us with when requesting additional information from us or from one or more of our clients. Examples of personally identifiable data that you may provide to us include name, address, phone and email address.

If you elect to provide the eMA with personally identifiable information, we may utilize such information for marketing purposes, and this use may result in follow-up communications from the eMA from our clients, or from third party services collecting information on behalf of our joint clients. In addition, that information may be combined with information collected from other sources to assist with targeting ads to your preferences and behaviors, and for other the eMA sales and marketing efforts.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

All personally identifiable information you provide is maintained in confidence by the eMA. There are instances, however, in which your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information is shared with third parties, as described below.

Your non-personally identifiable data may be shared with third-party partners of the eMA.com on an anonymous basis.

When you request information from the eMA or one or more of our sponsors, advertisers or clients, we may transfer that information within the eMA or route your information to our sponsors, advertisers or clients directly or via third parties, so that they may provide the information on their product or service.

We may also disclose information to an affiliate or third party who provides services we deem relevant. In such situations, you will always be provided with an opportunity to opt-out of receiving this information. Please be aware that the eMA is careful in selecting companies with whom it does business.

In addition to the above situations where your information may be shared with others, there is also the possibility that the eMA, or part(s) of our parent company, may one day be purchased by, or merged with, another company. In the event of such transaction, the acquiring (or merging) company will have access to all collected personally identifiable information.

Finally, the eMA may share your information as necessary to comply with a court order or to cooperate with government and law enforcement officials.

**Newsletters**

As a subscriber or visitor to the eMA site, you may sign up for one of our free or paid newsletters. When you sign up for one of the newsletters, we ask for contact information, such as your name and e-mail address, and job and job title information, which are used to help us understand our audience. Additionally, if you decide that you do not wish to receive a newsletter or update any longer, you may cancel it by opting out via the links at the bottom of e-mails you receive.

**Surveys**

Surveys are another method by which we gather information about eMA visitors. From time to time, we request subscribers’ or newsletter subscribers’ input in order to evaluate potential features and services. The decision to answer a survey is completely yours. We use information gathered from surveys to improve our service.

**Tell-A-Friend**

If you elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask you for the friend’s name and email address. The eMA will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. eMA stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

**Social Media**

The eMA utilizes several types of social media platforms.  Each has its own privacy policy and terms of service.  Posts and interactions made on the eMA site may also be displayed within social media platforms.

**How Do We Protect Subscriber Information Once We Have It?**

All information is stored on a secure server. The eMA uses a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) enabled server for our Web site. Browsers will encrypt the contents of the subscription form before sending it to our server.

**Cookies You Can’t Eat**

**What Is a Cookie and Why Do We Use Them?**

A “cookie” is a small piece of information sent by a Web server to store in a Web browser so that it can later be read back from that browser. The eMA uses cookies to store some personal preferences for your future visits. Cookies allow the eMA to recognize you more quickly; therefore, your time spent on our site is more personalized and productive. You’ll find that cookies are an industry standard and are used at most major Web sites in much the same way we use them here at the eMA. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the eMA site functionality.

We use in-house and one or more third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site, as well as when we serve the eMA buttons, banners, badges, videos or other content on member sites or other third-party websites. In the course of serving advertisements, we or our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique “cookie” on your browser. While the cookie we set may be tied to your specific personal information we also may set anonymous cookies and all third party cookie data is anonymous. The eMA uses the anonymous information it collects to customize the advertisements that consumers see on participating web sites and to analyze if the advertising resulted in sales, clicks or other activity. In accordance with applicable laws and regulations, the eMA will also disclose this information in response to subpoenas, court orders and other required legal processes.

The eMA and/or these companies may use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to the eMA and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that might be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here.

In order to make the eMA a more valuable product for our subscribers and visitors, we also collect and analyze statistical information. From time to time, we share this information in aggregate with third parties. However, this data is reported only in aggregate and reveals no personal details about individual visitors to our site. This information is distributed only to help attract appropriate advertisers for the the eMA site.

**Your Consent**

By using our Web site and signing up for the eMA services, you consent to the collection and use of the previously mentioned information by the eMA.

Updating Your Information or Opting Out

You can edit or discontinue your newsletter/e-mail status at any time.

To discontinue receiving all e-mail communications from the eMA:

Click the link at the bottom of any e-mail that indicates “unsubscribe” or update e-mail preferences” and follow the instructions.

The eMA periodically communicates information about a customer’s account and or subscription service — e-mails containing account set-up instructions, renewal notices, and information about product changes. For these types of communications, we must maintain an open channel to our customers to ensure the integrity of our service, and therefore cannot unsubscribe those individuals.

**Links to Other Companies**

Our websites contain many links to other company websites and to products and services offered by our business partners. Our privacy and security policies do not apply to these companies, so please check the privacy statements posted before you provide these companies with your personal information.

Contact Information:

The eMA

Attn: Customer Support

330 Old Country Road, Suite 206

Mineola, NY 11501

E-mail: [admin@emarketingassociation.com](mailto:admin@emarketingassociation.com)
